https://www.whsfl.com/notice-of-privacy-practices/

Call (772) 219-1080 |
HomeJeuneNu AestheticsWHS Women’s Health SpecialistAboutOur TeamFrequently Asked QuestionsEmployment OpportunitiesOB/GYN ServicesDa Vinci HysterectomyHologic 3DMedtronicPelvic HealthIUD’sMyosureEndometrial AblationUrodynamic TestingSingle-incision LaparoscopyInterstim ImplantsInterstitial CystitisUrinary IncontinenceAesthetic ServicesTextFat ReductionCoolSculptingInjectables & FillersBotoxJuvedermVolumaVolbellaLaser TreatmentsVascular TreatmentsPigment Skin DiscolorationHair RemovalJeuneNu Specials & News
View Our Current Specials
Signup to be notified of upcoming specials
First Name Email (required) *Select list(s) to subscribe to Example: Yes, I would like to receive emails from Women's Health Specialists. (You can unsubscribe anytime)Constant Contact Use.By submitting this form, you are consenting to receive marketing emails from: Women's Health Specialist and JeuneNu Aesthetic Beauty & Laser Center, Women's Health Specialists, Jensen Beach, FL, 34957, http://www.jeunenu.com. You can revoke your consent to receive emails at any time by using the SafeUnsubscribe® link, found at the bottom of every email. Emails are serviced by Constant ContactClinical Facial TreatmentsMicrodermabrasionVI PeelsVI Peels with PrecisionZO Ossential Stimulator PeelFacials & Aesthetic ArtsThe Pregnancy Pamper FacialDeep DetoxThe Signature JeuneNu FacialRetail ProductsZo MedicalRevision Skin CareLatisseSkinMedicaBlincTizoSilcSkinPatient InfoMedical RecordsPATIENT PORTAL LOGINMake an AppointmentInsurance & Managed CareGYN Patient InformationOB Patient InformationContactJensen Beach BranchPort St. Lucie Branch
Notice of Privacy Practices
admin
2019-09-24T10:30:02+00:00
THIS NOTICE DESCRIBES HOW MEDICAL INFORMATION ABOUT YOU MAY BE USED OR DISCLOSED AND HOW YOU CAN GET ACCESS TO THIS INFORMATION. PLEASE REVIEW IT CAREFULLY.
Effective Date: September 23, 2013
This is the first revision of this notice.
IF YOU HAVE ANY QUESTIONS ABOUT THIS NOTICE OR IF YOU NEED MORE INFORMATION, PLEASE CONTACT OUR PRIVACY OFFICER:
Privacy Officer:	Women’s Health Specialists Practice Administrator
Mailing Address:	3498 NW Federal Hwy, Jensen Beach, FL
34957
Telephone: 	772.219.1080
Fax:	772.219.1070
About This Notice
We are required by law to maintain the privacy of Protected Health Information and to give you this Notice explaining our privacy practices with regard to that information. You have certain rights – and we have certain legal obligations – regarding the privacy of your Protected Health Information, and this Notice also explains your rights and our obligations. We are required to abide by the terms of the current version of this Notice.
What is Protected Health Information?
“Protected Health Information” is information that individually identifies you and that we create or get from you or from another health care provider, health plan, your employer, or a health care clearinghouse and that relates to (1) your past, present, or future physical or mental health or conditions, (2) the provision of health care to you, or (3) the past, present, or future payment for your health care.
How We May Use and Disclose Your Protected Health Information
We may use and disclose your Protected Health Information in the following circumstances:
For Treatment. We may use or
disclose your Protected Health Information to give you medical treatment or
services and to manage and coordinate your medical care. For example, your
Protected Health Information may be provided to a physician or other health
care provider (e.g., a specialist or laboratory) to whom you have been referred
to ensure that the physician or other health care provider has the necessary
information to diagnose or treat you or provide you with a service.
For Payment. We may use and
disclose your Protected Health Information so that we can bill for the
treatment and services you receive from us and can collect payment from you, a
health plan, or a third party. This use and disclosure may include certain
activities that your health insurance plan may undertake before it approves or
pays for the health care services we recommend for you, such as making a
determination of eligibility or coverage for insurance benefits, reviewing
services provided to you for medical necessity, and undertaking utilization
review activities.  For example, we may
need to give your health plan information about your treatment in order for
your health plan to agree to pay for that treatment.
For Health Care
Operations. We may use and disclose Protected Health Information for our health care
operations. For example, we may use your Protected Health Information to
internally review the quality of the treatment and services you receive and to
evaluate the performance of our team members in caring for you. We also may
disclose information to physicians, nurses, medical technicians, medical
students, and other authorized personnel for educational and learning purposes.
Appointment
Reminders/Treatment Alternatives/Health-Related Benefits and Services. We may use and
disclose Protected Health Information to contact you to remind you that you
have an appointment for medical care, or to contact you to tell you about
possible treatment options or alternatives or health related benefits and
services that may be of interest to you.
Minors. We may disclose
the Protected Health Information of minor children to their parents or
guardians unless such disclosure is otherwise prohibited by law.
Research. We may use and
disclose your Protected Health Information for research purposes, but we will
only do that if the research has been specially approved by an authorized
institutional review board or a privacy board that has reviewed the research
proposal and has set up protocols to ensure the privacy of your Protected
Health Information. Even without that special approval, we may permit
researchers to look at Protected Health Information to help them prepare for
research, for example, to allow them to identify patients who may be included
in their research project, as long as they do not remove, or take a copy of,
any Protected Health Information. We may use and disclose a limited data set
that does not contain specific readily identifiable information about you for
research. However, we will only disclose the limited data set if we enter into
a data use agreement with the recipient who must agree to (1) use the data set
only for the purposes for which it was provided, (2) ensure the confidentiality
and security of the data, and (3) not identify the information or use it to
contact any individual.
As Required by
Law. We will disclose Protected Health Information about you when required to do so
by international, federal, state, or local law.
To Avert a
Serious Threat to Health or Safety. We may use and disclose Protected
Health Information when necessary to prevent a serious threat to your health or
safety or to the health or safety of others. But we will only disclose the
information to someone who may be able to help prevent the threat.
Business
Associates. We may disclose Protected Health Information to our business associates who
perform functions on our behalf or provide us with services if the Protected
Health Information is necessary for those functions or services. For example,
we may use another company to do our billing, or to provide transcription or
consulting services for us.  All of our
business associates are obligated, under contract with us, to protect the
privacy and ensure the security of your Protected Health Information.
Organ and Tissue
Donation. If you are an organ or tissue donor, we may use or disclose your Protected
Health Information to organizations that handle organ procurement or
transplantation – such as an organ donation bank – as necessary to facilitate
organ or tissue donation and transplantation.
Military and
Veterans. If you are a member of the armed forces, we may disclose Protected Health
Information as required by military command authorities. We also may disclose
Protected Health Information to the appropriate foreign military authority if
you are a member of a foreign military.
Workers’
Compensation. We
may use or disclose Protected Health Information for workers’ compensation or
similar programs that provide benefits for work-related injuries or illness.
Public Health
Risks. We
may disclose Protected Health Information for public health activities. This
includes disclosures to: (1) a person subject to the jurisdiction of the Food
and Drug Administration (“FDA”) for purposes related to the quality, safety or
effectiveness of an FDA-regulated product or activity; (2) prevent or control
disease, injury or disability; (3) report births and deaths; (4) report child
abuse or neglect; (5) report reactions to medications or problems with
products; (6) notify people of recalls of products they may be using; and (7) a
person who may have been exposed to a disease or may be at risk for contracting
or spreading a disease or condition.
Abuse, Neglect,
or Domestic Violence.  We may disclose Protected Health Information
to the appropriate government authority if we believe a patient has been the
victim of abuse, neglect, or domestic violence and the patient agrees or we are
required or authorized by law to make that disclosure.
Health Oversight
Activities. We may disclose Protected Health Information to a health oversight agency for
activities authorized by law. These oversight activities include, for example,
audits, investigations, inspections, licensure, and similar activities that are
necessary for the government to monitor the health care system, government
programs, and compliance with civil rights laws.
Data Breach
Notification Purposes. We may use or disclose your Protected Health
Information to provide legally required notices of unauthorized access to or
disclosure of your health information.
Lawsuits and
Disputes. If
you are involved in a lawsuit or a dispute, we may disclose Protected Health
Information in response to a court or administrative order. We also may
disclose Protected Health Information in response to a subpoena, discovery
request, or other legal process from someone else involved in the dispute, but
only if efforts have been made to tell you about the request or to get an order
protecting the information requested. We may also use or disclose your
Protected Health Information to defend ourselves in the event of a lawsuit.
Law Enforcement. We may disclose
Protected Health Information, so long as applicable legal requirements are met,
for law enforcement purposes.
Military
Activity and National Security. If you are involved with military,
national security or intelligence activities or if you are in law enforcement
custody, we may disclose your Protected Health Information to authorized
officials so they may carry out their legal duties under the law.
Coroners, Medical
Examiners, and Funeral Directors. We may disclose Protected Health
Information to a coroner, medical examiner, or funeral director so that they
can carry out their duties.
Inmates. If you are an
inmate of a correctional institution or under the custody of a law enforcement
official, we may disclose Protected Health Information to the correctional
institution or law enforcement official if the disclosure is necessary (1) for
the institution to provide you with health care; (2) to protect your health and
safety or the health and safety of others; or (3) the safety and security of
the correctional institution.
Uses and Disclosures That Require Us to Give You an Opportunity to Object and Opt Out
Individuals
Involved in Your Care or Payment for Your Care. Unless you
object, we may disclose to a member of your family, a relative, a close friend
or any other person you identify, your Protected Health Information that
directly relates to that person’s involvement in your health care.  If you are unable to agree or object to such
a disclosure, we may disclose such information as necessary if we determine
that it is in your best interest based on our professional judgment.
Disaster Relief. We may disclose
your Protected Health Information to disaster relief organizations that seek
your Protected Health Information to coordinate your care, or notify family and
friends of your location or condition in a disaster. We will provide you with
an opportunity to agree or object to such a disclosure whenever we practicably
can do so.
Fundraising
Activities.  We may use or
disclose your Protected Health Information, as necessary, in order to contact
you for fundraising activities. You have the right to opt out of receiving
fundraising communications.  If you do not
want to receive these materials, please submit a written request to the Privacy
Officer.
Your Written Authorization is Required
for Other Uses and Disclosures
The
following uses and disclosures of your Protected Health Information will be
made only with your written authorization:
Most uses and disclosures of
psychotherapy notes;
Uses and disclosures of
Protected Health Information for marketing purposes; and
Disclosures that constitute a sale of
your Protected Health Information.
Other
uses and disclosures of Protected Health Information not covered by this Notice
or the laws that apply to us will be made only with your written authorization.
If you do give us an authorization, you may revoke it at any time by submitting
a written revocation to our Privacy Officer and we will no longer disclose
Protected Health Information under the authorization. But disclosure that we
made in reliance on your authorization before you revoked it will not be
affected by the revocation.
Your Rights Regarding Your Protected Health Information
You have the following rights, subject to certain limitations, regarding your Protected Health Information:
Right to Inspect
and Copy. You have the right to inspect and copy Protected Health Information that may be
used to make decisions about your care or payment for your care. We have up to
30 days to make your Protected Health Information available to you and we may
charge you a reasonable fee for the costs of copying, mailing or other supplies
associated with your request. We may not charge you a fee if you need the
information for a claim for benefits under the Social Security Act or any other
state or federal needs-based benefit program. We may deny your request in
certain limited circumstances. If we do deny your request, you have the right
to have the denial reviewed by a licensed healthcare professional who was not
directly involved in the denial of your request, and we will comply with the
outcome of the review.
Right to a
Summary or Explanation. We can also provide you
with a summary of your Protected Health Information, rather than the entire
record, or we can provide you with an explanation of the Protected Health
Information which has been provided to you, so long as you agree to this
alternative form and pay the associated fees.
Right to an
Electronic Copy of Electronic Medical Records. If your
Protected Health Information is maintained in an electronic format (known as an
electronic medical record or an electronic health record), you have the right
to request that an electronic copy of your record be given to you or
transmitted to another individual or entity. We will make every effort to provide access to your Protected
Health Information in the form or format you request,
if it is readily producible in such form or format. If the Protected Health Information is not readily producible in the form or format you
request your record will be provided in either our standard electronic format
or if you do not want this form or format, a readable
hard copy form. We may charge
you a reasonable, cost-based fee for the labor associated with transmitting the
electronic medical record.
How to Exercise Your Rights
To exercise your rights described in this Notice, send your request, in writing, to our Privacy Officer at the address listed at the beginning of this Notice. We may ask you to fill out a form that we will supply. To exercise your right to inspect and copy your Protected Health Information, you may also contact your physician directly. To get a paper copy of this Notice, contact our Privacy Officer by phone or mail.
Changes To This Notice
We reserve the right to change this Notice. We reserve the right to make the changed Notice effective for Protected Health Information we already have as well as for any Protected Health Information we create or receive in the future. A copy of our current Notice is posted in our office and on our website.
Complaints
You may file a complaint with us or with the Secretary of the United States Department of Health and Human Services if you believe your privacy rights have been violated.
To file a complaint with us, contact our Privacy Officer at the address listed at the beginning of this Notice. All complaints must be made in writing and should be submitted within 180 days of when you knew or should have known of the suspected violation. There will be no retaliation against you for filing a complaint.
To file a complaint with the Secretary, mail it to: Secretary of the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, 200 Independence Ave, S.W., Washington, D.C. 20201. Call (202) 619-0257 (or toll free (877) 696-6775) or go to the website of the Office for Civil Rights, www.hhs.gov/ocr/hipaa/, for more information. There will be no retaliation against you for filing a complaint.
Port St. Lucie, FL 34986
Call
772 219-1080
Women’s Health Specialists, Jensen Beach, FL
